[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "out of the given alternatives, choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word:-IMPROVEMENT",
    "options": ["Betterment", "Advancement", "Promotion", "Preference"],
    "answer": "Betterment"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "choose the one that best expresses the meaning of the given word AMICABLE",
    "options": ["Interesting", "Loving", "Affectionate", "Friendly"],
    "answer": "Friendly"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word:-LIABILITY",
    "options": ["Debt", "Treasure", "Property", "Assets"],
    "answer": "Assets"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "choose the word opposite in meaning to the given word: HATE",
    "options": ["Abhor", "Concern", "Admire", "Loathe"],
    "answer": "Admire"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Choose the one which can be substituted for the given words/sentence:-A song embodying religious and sacred emotions-",
    "options": ["Hymn", "Ode", "Lyric", "Ballad"],
    "answer": "Hymn"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Time after twilight and before night-",
    "options": ["Eclipse", "Dusk", "Dawn", "Evening"],
    "answer": "Dusk"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Fill in the blanks in the following sentences by selecting the most appropriate alternative from among the four choices given: Parliamentary democracy demands discipline --- to the rules.",
    "options": ["Knowledge", "Respectful", "Adherence", "Awareness"],
    "answer": "Adherence"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Reason is the highest faculty---on human by their creator.",
    "options": ["Bestowed", "Entrusted", "Endowed", "Conferred"],
    "answer": "Bestowed"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Rishan walks as if he---lame.",
    "options": ["Had been", "Has", "Were", "Is"],
    "answer": "Were"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "one of the four sentences given in each question is grammatically wrong. That alternative is your answer:-",
    "options": [
      "Laziness is detrimental for success",
      "Neither you nor i am in a sound position.",
      "He begged the favour of my granting him leave",
      "Your action is not in conformity with the law"
    ],
    "answer": "Laziness is detrimental for success"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "one of the four sentences given in each question is grammatically wrong. That alternative is your answer:-",
    "options": [
      "He has no desire for fame",
      "He is too miserly to part with his money",
      "He has invited me for dinner",
      "I intend going to Rajshahi"
    ],
    "answer": "I intend going to Rajshahi"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Each of the following idioms is followed by some alternatives. choose the one which best expresses its meaning:-To keep one's head-",
    "options": [
      "To save oneself",
      "To be self respectful",
      "To keep calm",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "To keep calm"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "To put the cart before the horse-----",
    "options": [
      "To reverse the natural order of things",
      "To raise obstacle",
      "To force a person to do something",
      "To offer a person what he cannot eat"
    ],
    "answer": "To reverse the natural order of things"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "To read between the lines----",
    "options": [
      "To concentrate",
      "To suspect",
      "To read carefully",
      "To grasp the hidden meaning"
    ],
    "answer": "To grasp the hidden meaning"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "\"\"\"I know him.\" Change the voice form\"",
    "options": [
      "He has been known by me",
      "He was known to me",
      "He is known to me",
      "He is known by me"
    ],
    "answer": "He is known to me"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Change voice form - A lion may be helped even by a little mouse.",
    "options": [
      "Even a little mouse may help a lion",
      "A little mouse may even help a lion",
      "A little mouse can even help a lion",
      "Even a little mouse ought to help a lion"
    ],
    "answer": "Even a little mouse may help a lion"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Choose the correctly spelt word:-",
    "options": ["Leisure", "Liesure", "Leasure", "Lesiure"],
    "answer": "Leisure"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Choose the correctly spelt word:-",
    "options": ["Supercede", "Supersede", "Superseed", "Superceed"],
    "answer": "Supersede"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "The horror movie scared them out of their-",
    "options": ["Seats", "Lives", "Wits", "Funds"],
    "answer": "Wits"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "The people who carry a coffin at a funeral are called-",
    "options": ["Pallbearers", "Undertakers", "Supporters", "Mourners"],
    "answer": "Pallbearers"
  }
]
